## Tyler T. Mullen

Email: Tmullen493@gmail.com | Phone: 612-644-7902 |

Location: New Hope, MN 55427

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-mullen-94905553/| GitHub: https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen| Website: https://Tyler-

Mullen.github.io/singlePagePortfolio/

### **SUMMARY**

Web developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and experience coding sorting algorithms and a compiler for mini-pascal using Java. Excels at teaching end-users how to use technologies and working in fast-paced environments with demanding deadlines that require communication with co-workers and clients. Leverages coding and troubleshooting skills to create web pages, applications and software.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Proficient with Java, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Firebase, phpMyAdmin, API's, Git, Git Bash, SQL, React.js, Express.js and MySQLWorkBench, Moment.js, Axios.js, Sorting Algorithms, MERN, User Training and Full Stack Development

#### **PROJECTS**

**Friend Finder** | <a href="https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/friendFinder">https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/friendFinder</a> https://vast-garden-65226.herokuapp.com/

- A ten-question quiz that matches the user to a set of friends that is saved in a JSON file and saves the user's scores for later.
- Uses Express.js to route the results to the JSON file and JSON to store objects form the API.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JSON, Express.js.

## LIRI Search Bot | https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/liri-node-app

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1l0zRhITL4Mlh4nKGg8R3EvpmeqNOs8QZ/view

- Allows the user to run searches for concert dates, movie information, and song information.
- Uses Spotify's API to search Spotify's database and Axios to search Bands-in-town and OMDB's database.
- Node.js, Moment, Spotify API, Axios, JavaScript.

# Train Scheduler | https://github.com/Tyler-Mullen/Train-Scheduler | https://Tyler-Mullen.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

- Adds trains to a schedule, displaying name, destination, and next arrival.
- Sends data to, and pull data from, firebase to display all scheduled trains.
- Firebase, Moment, JavaScript, CSS, HTML.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Back of House Team Member-Chick-Fil-A - Bloomington, MN

2017 - 2019

- Cultivating strong relationships with co-workers and demonstrating a calm composure during busy and stressful periods.
- First team member (out of 35) to complete a rigorous online training program set up by franchise operator.

#### <u>Technical Consultant</u> – Allina Health – Minneapolis, MN

2016 - 2017

- Assisted approximately fifty Allina Health patients per day by recovering login information, resetting passwords, and changing account information.
- Knowledgeable in Allina Health's Patient Portal and MyChart, and explained features and benefits to patients.
- Created and processed MyChart user login for new patients.

## Intern - Lifeworks - Eagan, MN

2016 - 2016

- Relocated and rewired approximately twenty computers during the facility's reorganization.
- Installed Windows 8 updates onto all computers.
- Managed the personal login updates for all 150+ staff members across six offices to ensure they would not be affected by a recent security breach.
- Effectively communicated with staff and executed the setup of IT equipment.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, graduated 2019.

Augsburg College, Minneapolis, MN – Bachelors of Arts In Computer Science, graduated 2016.